（綱手つなで）久しぶりだな ２人とも
It's been a long time, you two.
修業の成果はあったんだろうな
I'm sure your training produced
good results, right?
（自来也じらいや）なんの成果もなしに
戻ってきたとでも思っとるのか？
Do you think we came back
without making progress?
（うずまきナルト）
バッチリだってばよ
It went perfectly!
Then show me
those results immediately.
（綱手）では 早速
成果を見せてもらおう
（ナルト）見せるって…
Show you...?
（綱手）ある男の相手をしてもらう
You will take on a particular man.
I didn't send him on any missions
for the past several days
このために わざわざ
ここ数日は任務にもつけず
and had him stand by
for this very purpose.
待機してもらっていたのだ
Your opponent will be...
その相手とは…
Come in!
（綱手）入れ！
あ…
Hello.
（奈良ならシカマル）どうも～
（春野はるのサクラ）
シカマル テマリさん
Shikamaru! Temari-san!
Look who's here!
ほら 誰だと思う？
（シカマル）あっ
（テマリ）んっ
Naruto.
（シカマル）ナルト
Hey! That is you isn't it, Naruto!
おい ナルトじゃねえか
（ナルト）あっ シカマル
Shikamaru!
This is... that midget...?
（テマリ）こいつ あのちびか
（シカマル）お前 帰ってきてたのか
So you're back?
ああ けさ帰ってきた
Yeah, I got back this morning.
（シカマル）ヘヘッ
なんかバカさ加減が抜けたっつうか
You don't look
as stupid as before...
I mean, hey, have you changed?
なんつうか…
変わったか？ おい
ん ヌヒヒヒ…
いや 変わってない
No, he hasn't.
（シカマル）ハハ… やっぱり
Oh... I thought so.
（ナルト）サクラちゃん
Sakura-chan...
（綱手）ハハハ…
（シズネ）フフフ
ん？ じゃあ 俺の相手は
シカマルってわけか？
Then, does this mean
you're my opponent, Shikamaru?
Opponent? What do you mean?
相手？ なんのことだ
俺は書類を届けに来ただけだぞ
I just came to deliver
some documents.
Huh? You're not
my opponent, Shikamaru?
（ナルト）ん？
シカマルじゃないのか
じゃあ…
Then...?
Who're you again?
誰だっけ？
覚えてないのか？
You don't remember me?
（綱手）ナルト
お前の相手はそっちじゃない
Naruto, that's not your opponent.
He's out there.
（綱手）あっちだ
（ナルト）ん？
おっ
You sure got tall... Naruto.
（はたけカカシ）
でかくなったな ナルト
Yo!
（カカシ）よっ！
あ…
カカシ先生
Kakashi-sensei!
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
The Akatsuki
Makes Its Move
（ナルト）先生ってば
全然 変わってねえってばよ
Sensei, you haven't changed one bit!
あっ そうだ
Oh yeah.
Listen, listen...
I've got a present for you, Sensei.
あのさ あのさ
カカシ先生にプレゼントが
あるんだってばよ
（カカシ）ん？
懐かしい光景だな
This is sure a nostalgic sight.
はい
Yes, it is...
（カカシ）なに～！
What?!
You got me... Th-This is...
お前 こ こ… これは…
（ナルト）これってば
This is the first new title in
the Make-Out series in three years!
イチャイチャシリーズ
３年ぶりの最新作
すんげえ つまんないけど
先生 好きなんだろ？
I think it's totally boring,
but you like this stuff,
don't you, Sensei?!
（自来也）ふん アホが
That idiot... No way could
a kid understand the appeal.
あのおもしろさが
ガキに分かってたまるかっての
おまけに まだ世間に出てない
レアものだってのに
And on top of that,
it's a very rare item that hasn't
even been released yet...
（カカシ）うおお…
よし！ お楽しみは
その辺で終わりだ カカシ
All right! That's enough fun
for now, Kakashi.
（ナルト）ん？
まさか 俺の相手って
Don't tell me...
Are you  my opponent...?
（カカシ）う～ん
ちょっと違うかな
Hmm, not quite...
いやあ サクラと会うのも
久しぶりだねえ
Gee, it's been a while
since I saw you too, Sakura.
（サクラ）はい カカシ先生
Yes, it has, Kakashi-sensei.
（カカシ）俺が相手するのは…
My opponent will be...
ナルト サクラ
Naruto... and Sakura,
the both of you!
お前ら２人だ
（サクラ）えっ
（ナルト）なっ…
カカシ先生が相手？
Kakashi-sensei's our opponent...
（綱手）カカシ相手にどれだけやれるか
I want to see what you
can do against Kakashi...
I will determine your status
in the future based on the results.
その結果いかんによって
今後の お前たちの処遇を決める
ん… 処遇ねえ
Status, eh?
サクラ お前とて
Sakura, show me that
ムダに 私の元で
過ごしたわけでもあるまい
you weren't just wasting
your time training under me.
Yes, ma'am!
はい
（カカシ）それじゃあ すぐに始めるか
Then, shall we get right to it?
（サクラ）ん…
（ナルト）あ…
（カカシ）…と言いたいところだけど
That's what I'd like  to say.
ナルトも帰ってきたばっかで
疲れているだろう
But since you just got back Naruto,
you must be tired.
少し休憩をやる
I'll give you a short rest.
I'm not particularly tired
or anything!
俺は 別に
疲れちゃいねえってばよ
（カカシ）あとで
第三演習場で落ち合おう
Let's meet up at
the Third Training Grounds later.
じゃあな
See ya.
（シズネ）どうしたんでしょう
あんなに急いで
Why's he in such a hurry?
だいたいの見当はつくがな
I have a pretty good idea...
本を読む気だな
He's going to read his book.
Oh!
ああ～
With that look he had,
there's no doubt about it.
あの顔は 間違いなくそうね
（自来也）発売前のわしの本を
手に入れたんじゃ
That's the obvious reaction
after getting an unreleased copy
of one of my books.
当然の反応だのォ
（ナルト）カカシ先生ってば
俺たちの修業の成果より
That Kakashi-sensei.
Is that stupid book
more important to him
あんなくだらない本のほうが
大切なのかよ
than the results of our training?
（サクラ）まあ そのおかげで
Well, now we can discuss our strategy
against Kakashi-sensei.
こっちは カカシ先生相手の戦略を
打ち合わせできるんだけど
んで…
So, are you guys on a date?
そちらはデートですかい？
んん… そんなんじゃねえよ
It's not like that.
ふんっ 冗談はよせ
なんで こんなヤツと
Heh! Cut out the jokes.
Why would I be on
a date with this guy?
もうすぐ中忍ちゅうにん試験がある
It's almost time for
the Chunin Exams.
その打ち合わせで 砂と木ノ葉このはを
行ったり来たりしてるだけだ
I've just been going back and forth
between the Sand and the Leaf
for meetings concerning the Exams.
んで めんどくせーが
俺 試験の係になってっから
And although it's a pain,
I've been put in charge
of the Exams...
砂の使者さんを案内するよう
言われてるだけだ
I've just been told to act as
a guide for the Sand messenger.
中忍試験か
Chunin Exams, huh...?
That sure takes me back...
懐かしいな
（シカマル）あっ
Oh...
んで お前 どうすんだ？ ナルト
So what're you going to do, Naruto?
（ナルト）あ？ 何が？
About what?
（シカマル）んっ 何がって…
中忍試験だよ
About the Chunin Exams.
俺らと同期で中忍になってないの
お前だけだぜ
You're the only one from our class
who hasn't become a Chunin.
びえ～
What?!
じゃ… じゃあ
サクラちゃんも中忍？
Th-Then, you're also a Chunin, Sakura-chan?
（サクラ）フフ～ン そうよ
Heh-heh... That's right.
ついでといっちゃ なんだが
砂隠れのカンクロウとこの人
And just for the record,
Kankuro, this person here,
and Neji who's one grade above us
are already Jonin.
あ～ それから１級上のネジは
もう上忍だ
（ナルト）かあ…
Huh?!
あっ
じゃあ 我愛羅があら　我愛羅は？
Then what about Gaara?!
（バキ）風影かぜかげ様 そろそろ会議です
Kazekage-sama...
The meeting is about to begin.
Okay.
（我愛羅）分かった
（ナルト）そうか
I see...
我愛羅は風影になったのか
So Gaara became the Kazekage, huh...?
すげえ
That's awesome...
（シカマル）あ？
俺も負けてらんねえってばよ
I won't be outdone!
ぜってえ火影ほかげになってやる
I'll become the Hokage,
no matter what!
見てろよ 我愛羅
Just you wait, Gaara!
（サクラ）やっぱり
少しは成長したみたい
I guess...
he has matured a little, after all.
（自来也）どうだ
おもしろいだろうのォ
What do you think?!
Pretty good, huh...?
わしの最高傑作だからのォ フフ…
It is my finest work.
約束どおり
ナルトはお前に預けるからの
I leave Naruto in your care
as promised...
（カカシ）あいつ 少しは
成長してればありがたいんですがねえ
It'd be nice if he's grown
at least a little.
ふんっ
抜かりがあると思うか？
Heh... You'd think I've slipped up?
気を抜くと お前も出し抜かれるぞ
You'll get beaten out
if you get careless.
（カカシ）そりゃ 頼もしい
Well, that's encouraging to hear.
ヤツらの動きが活発になってきた
And their actions are
gaining momentum.
（バキ）
この数年で わが里の力は安定し
Over the past several years,
the strength of our village
has stabilized,
各同盟国の隠れ里との交流も
豊かなものになりました
and relations with the Hidden Villages
in each allied land have prospered.
（バキ）特に 新人育成には
In particular,
we have achieved good results
木こノ葉は隠がくれの演習プログラムを
取り入れたカリキュラムで
in our development of recruits
with the curriculum incorporating...
高い成果が出ています
the training program
from the Leaf Village.
（砂忍の上役）
もうすぐ中忍試験だな
The Chunin Exams are almost here.
I look forward to the results.
そりゃあ 結果が楽しみだわい
（由良ゆうら）ただ
However... at this time,
with the Chunin Exams upon us,
また中忍試験のこの時期に
よからぬうわさが
there is a nasty rumor
going around...
なんだ由良
What is it, Yuura?
暁あかつきという組織の名を
聞いたことがありますか？
Have you heard of the organization
called the "Akatsuki"?
I see... So they're finally
making their move.
（カカシ）そうですか
ヤツらがついに
It's something we were expecting
to a degree, though.
（自来也）ある程度
予想されていたことではあるがのォ
うん
（カカシ）暁か
The Akatsuki, huh...?
（由良）暁というのは
The Akatsuki is a mysterious organization
composed of a dozen or so Shinobi.
十数名ほどの
忍びによって構成されている...
謎の組織です
メンバーはいずれも
The members of the organization
are vicious S-Rank criminals
ビンゴブックに載ってる
凶悪なＳ級犯罪者ばかりです
all listed in the Bingo Book.
面の割れているものの中には
Of those identified...
木ノ葉隠れ里出身で
there is Uchiha Itachi from
the Village Hidden in the Leaves
一夜にして みずからの一族を
滅亡に追い込んだ
who drove his own clan
to annihilation in one night.
うちはイタチ
かつては 忍刀しのびがたな七人衆の１人で
霧隠きりがくれの怪人と呼ばれた
There is one who was once a member of
the Seven Ninja Swords Men of the Mist.
He was known as
the phantom of the Mist.
干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ
Hoshigaki Kisame.
以前 木ノ葉崩しを画策し
先代の風影様を暗殺した大蛇丸おろちまるも
And there is the one who once
plotted the destruction of the Leaf...
and assassinated the
previous Kazekage-sama.
Orochimaru.
かつては この組織の
メンバーだったといわれています
It is said he used to be
a member of this organization.
（カカシ）ヤツらが派手な動きを
見せ始めている理由は なんです？
Why have they started taking
such dramatic action?
目的は？
What's their goal?
そこまでは わしにも分からん
That's beyond me at this point...
What I do know...
分かっとるのは…
ナルトの中のものを
狙っとるということ
is that they're after
what's inside Naruto.
そして
And... that they've got something evil
in mind.
何か よからぬことを
考えとるということじゃ
各国の警備担当者には
情報を流しておいた
I passed on this information
to those in charge of security
for each land.
すぐに 警戒態勢を
敷いてくれるとよいのだがのォ
I sure hope they tighten up
their security immediately.
うん
そうか
I see... I'd heard the rumors...
うわさだけは
耳にしたことがあるが
例の組織が ついに…
So the organization in question
is finally taking action...
情報源が あの伝説の三忍さんにんの１人
自来也様でしたので
The source of the information
is one of the legendary Sannin.
Jiraiya-sama.
勝手とは思いましたが
So prior to the meeting,
会議に先んじて
里を固める命を出しておきました
I took the liberty of issuing an order
to increase Village security.
里周辺の要所には すでに
暗部あんぶの手練てだれも配置してあります
Anbu Black Ops masters
have already been stationed
at key points around the village.
いかに力のある忍といえど
No matter how powerful
the Shinobi may be,
力ずくで侵入することは
できないでしょう
they will not be able
to infiltrate by force.
暁のメンバーは
I hear the members of the Akatsuki
wear black clothing
黒い衣に赤い雲模様のマントを
着用していると聞きます
in addition to capes with
a red cloud pattern on them.
そのようなものが現れたときは
I ordered security to attack
with full force
全力でたたくように
命じておきました
should they see someone
fitting that description.
（バキ）では これで
会議は終わりにする
Now then...
the meeting is adjourned.
さすがだな 由良よ
いち早く動いていたとは
Well done, Yuura.
I never thought you'd take action
so quickly.
（由良）フフッ
私も 上役を４年も
務めさせていただている身です
I have also served as
a superior for four years.
里のためには…
It is my intention...
to always make decisions
while considering...
どうするのが…
いちばんよいか…
（上役）ん？
（由良）常に… 考えて…
what's in the best interest...
of the... village.
判断している…
つもり… です…
SEAL
あっ あ…
う…
（上役）どうした？
What's the matter?
（由良）いえ なんでもありません
Nothing... It's nothing at all...
少し寝不足で
I just haven't slept much...
そうか
体には気をつけろよ
I see... You need to take care
of yourself.
（由良）ありがとうございます
Thank you for your concern.
んん…
（由良）そうか そうだったな
I see... That's right...
（デイダラ）そうか
I see. So we have to deal
with this one,
大蛇丸のところにやったヤツより
こっちが先か
then go after the guy
we sent to Orochimaru, huh?
It seems he turned traitor
and leaked information about us.
どうやら オイラたちの情報を
垂れ流しにするような
裏切り者になってるらしいが うん
（サソリ）しかたねえだろうが
It can't be helped.
術をかけたあとどうなるかなんて
俺は知らん
Even I don't know what happens
after the Jutsu is cast.
それより その袋だけで
大丈夫なのか？
More importantly,
will just that bag be enough?
相手は人柱力じんちゅうりきを使うんだぜ
Our opponent will be
using the Jinchuriki.
（デイダラ）オイラの術は
すべて芸術だ
All of my Jutsu are works of art.
それに ちゃ～んと
オハコも持ってきている うん
And I made sure to
bring my specialty.
なんせ相手は一尾だからな うん
After all, our opponent
is the One-Tailed.
"Third Training Grounds"
ああ～ もう
カカシ先生ってば
いつまで待たせる気だよ
Is Kakashi-sensei
going to make us wait forever?!
まっ 昔っからだけどね
Well, he's always been like this.
（ナルト）は～ 全く…
Geez, it'd be nice if he'd show
a little improvement.
ちょっとは進歩してほしいってばよ
フフッ
（ナルト）あ…
Oh, sorry about that.
（カカシ）やあ わりい わりい
実は ここに来る途中で
おばあさんが困ってて…
As it happens, I ran into an old woman
in trouble on my way here and...
（ナルト･サクラ）はい それウソ！
- Okay! That's a lie!
なんか懐かしいってばよ ここ
This place...
kind of takes me back.
うん
（カカシ）本日の課題
Your task for today is
それは この鈴を
俺から昼までに奪い取ることだ
to take these bells away from me
by this afternoon.
奪えなかったものは昼飯抜き！
Those unable to get a bell
will get no lunch.
（ナルト）えっ！
What?!
（カカシ）あれに縛りつけた上
目の前で 俺が弁当食うから
You'll be tied to those posts and
then I'll eat your lunch right
in front of you.
（カカシ）あ～ そういや
Oh, come to think of it,
ここは お前たちの
最初の演習場所だったっけなあ
this was your first Training Ground,
wasn't it?
第七班
Squad Seven...
スリーマンセルか
The Three-Man Squad, huh...?
（カカシ）あのときは
サスケもいたっけな
We had Sasuke with us...
back then, didn't we?
（サクラ）行かないで！
Don't go!
行くなら 私 大声出して…
If you do, I'll scream...!
（サスケ）サクラ
Sakura.
ありがとう
Thanks.
（サクラ）あ…
サスケ君…
Sasuke...kun...
サスケ！
Sasuke!
（サスケ）よう
Yo, useless.
ウスラトンカチ
（カカシ）ん？
（ナルト）俺ってば なんであのとき…
（カカシ）サスケの名前は
こいつらには禁句だな
Sasuke's name is
off limits for these guys...
（鈴の音）
（ナルト）あっ
（カカシ）まっ
どれだけ成長したのか見てやる
Well... Let's see how much
you've grown.
サスケのことは
諦めちゃいないんだろ？
You haven't given up
on Sasuke, have you?
（サクラ）もちろん
Absolutely not!
そのために 修業を
積んできたんだってばよ
That's why I continued my training!
（カカシ）うん
ルールは 初めてお前たちと
会ったときと同じ
The rules are the same
as when we first met.
どんな手を使ってもいいから
俺から鈴を取ればいい
I don't care how you do it.
Just take a bell away from me.
（カカシ）俺を…
（ナルト）殺すつもりでこないと
- If you don't...
- "come at me with the intent to kill,"
取れないから… でしょ？
"we won't be able to get the bells", right?
（カカシ）手裏剣しゅりけん使ってもいいぞ～
You can use Shuriken
if you want.
俺を殺す気でこないと
取れないからな
If you don't come at me
with the intent to kill,
you won't be able to get the bells.
（カカシ）フッ そのとおり
Exactly.
俺を殺すつもりでこないと
取れないからな
If you don't come at me
with the intent to kill,
you won't be able to get the bells.
期限は あしたの日の出まで
You have until sunrise tomorrow.
さて 始めますか
Now then, shall we begin?
今度は その本
読みながらやらないの？
You're not going to do it
while reading your book
this time around, Kakashi-sensei?
カカシ先生
それとも もう
読み終わっちゃったんですか？
Or have you already
finished reading?
（カカシ）いや 楽しみは
あとに取っとこうと思ってね
Nope... I thought I'd save
the fun for later...
それに まあ
今回は なんとなく…
Besides...
Well, I kind of get the feeling...
俺も少し…
I may have to...
本気を出さないといけない
雰囲気だしな
get a bit serious this time around.
（鈴の音）
（警邏けいら忍者）ん？
（警邏忍者）なんだ？
What's that...?
う…
黒い衣に赤い雲模様
Black clothing and
a red cloud pattern.
まさか
Don't tell me...
あれは…
Is that...?
由良隊長に 至急 連絡を
Contact Captain Yuura immediately!
（警邏忍者）あっ
由良隊長 例の組織のヤツらが
現れました
Captain Yuura!
Some guys from the organization
in question have shown up.
（由良）分かっている
I know.
心配するな すぐ終わる
You don't need to worry...
It'll be over soon.
（サソリ）ご苦労 由良
Good work, Yuura.
俺のこと思い出してくれた？
Do you remember me?
（由良）はっ サソリ様
Yes, Sasori-sama!
いくぞ～！
Let's go!
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
The time to unveil
my newest work has come.
この わしの新作が
ついにベールを脱ぐときがきた
It's been three years
since my previous masterpiece,
あの名作 イチャイチャ
バイオレンスから はや３年
"Make-Out Violence."
これぞ 時間を忘れ 呼吸を忘れ
You'll forget about time, forget to breathe,
and forget yourself with this,
我をも忘れる魂の最高傑作
a masterpiece filled with soul.
「イチャイチャタクティクス」
Pre-orders for "Make-Out Tactics"
木ノ葉集英堂しゅうえいどうにて
絶賛 予約受付中
are now being accepted
at the Leaf Shuueidou.
Buy it now, everyone! Okay?
みんな 買えのォ
Stop advertising your book here!
ここで宣伝すんな こら～！
次回「修業の成果」
Next time: "The Results of Training"
The Results of Training
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
（うみのイルカ）よ～し
全員 そろったようだな
All right, looks like everyone is here!
CHUNIN EXAM
きょうの授業は
中忍選抜試験について復習していくぞ
For today's class, we'll be reviewing
about the Chunin Exam.
いいな
Everyone ready?
LAND OF EARTH
LAND OF LIGHTNING
LAND OF FIRE
LAND OF WATER
LAND OF WIND
火の国と同盟を
結ぶ各国の隠れ里では
Twice per year, allied nations
with the Land of Fire
年に２回 合同で
優秀な下忍を集め
would gather outstanding Genin
from their hidden villages
to hold the Chunin Exam.
中忍選抜試験を開催している
Aside from promoting a Genin to Chunin,
JONIN
CHUNIN
GENIN
下忍から中忍へ
昇格させる
だけでなく
CHUNIN SELECTION EXAMS
it is also a place to show off
the land's military power
各国を
統治する大名に
その国の軍事力を
to the ruling Feudal Lords
of each nation.
アピールする
場でもある
Well, you could say that it's a battle
for your homeland's honor and prestige.
まあ つまり
己の国の名誉と威信を賭けた
戦いだといっても
過言ではないわけだ
それでは ここで問題だ
Now then, here's a question for you all.
ナルトたちが
参加した試験で
Which Leaf Ninja were promoted
to Chunin from the exam
みごと
中忍に昇格した
Naruto and the others participated in?
木ノ葉の忍は誰か
分かるかな？
NARUTO
SASUKE
SHIKAMARU
NEJI
The answer is:
正解は…
Nara Shikamaru.
奈良ならシカマルだ
Always saying “What a pain”,
he's now a full-fledged Chunin!
めんどくせーが
口癖のあいつも
今は中忍
Hm? Wait, does that mean
he's the same rank as me?!
っていうと
あいつ 俺と同じ階級か？
To be continued...